Brian Martin

1767 Pearl St #108 Denver, CO 80203 bmartin@attrition.org

### **SUMMARY**

An industry leading information security and risk management veteran with an extensive knowledge base and international experience. Understands the application of security concepts across a broad scope of information technology areas and industries. Extensive history in network and application penetration testing, security auditing, as well as vulnerability database management. Proven leadership, client influencing, and negotiation skills.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Tenable Network Security, Denver, Colorado

July 2008 - Present

Home: 303-832-9194

Mobile: 303-520-7283

## **Senior Nessus Analyst**

Subject Matter Expert for the Nessus vulnerability scanner and Content Group member. Performed a wide variety of writing including authoring documentation for products, knowledge base articles, and blogs. Provided feedback, quality assurance testing, and feature enhancement requests for Nessus and PVS. Helped monitor and maintain Tenable's public presence via the company blog, discussion forums, and Twitter. Contributed detailed concepts and input for the development of plugins for advanced web application assessments.

BT INS, Denver, Colorado

August 2006 – July 2008

# **Senior Security Consultant**

Senior consultant and practice leader of the Ethical Hacking (EH) group. Performed a wide variety of security assessments focused on web applications, perimeter network, internal network, social engineering, zero knowledge and physical audits. Primary maintainer of EH group documentation for reporting, author of several internal methodologies and senior member of document quality review board.

#### SELF EMPLOYED, Denver, Colorado

March 2003 – August 2006

# **Independent Consultant**

Performed a variety of subcontracting work for several companies (FuGEN, Delphinus, Wizard's Keys, True North Solutions, META Security, and more) doing network audit, ST&E/C&A evaluation, penetration testing, capacity planning, report review and more. Primary clients include US Government agencies, private banks and commercial entities.

# FuGEN TECHNOLOGIES, Rockville, Maryland

September 2002 – March 2003

#### **Senior Network Security Engineer**

Primary duties include leading penetration teams, performing ST&E/C&A evaluations and developing tools to support these efforts. Primary clients include National Park Services (NPS) and Bureau of Land Management (BLM).

CACI, Lanham, Maryland

March 2000 – June 2002

### Senior Network Security Engineer

Primary duties included leading penetration teams on multiple engagements for private and government sectors. Work included guiding the teams on methodology, product selection, testing methods and more. Primary clients included US Department of Justice and US Bureau of the Census.

Resume: Brian Martin 2

### SELF EMPLOYED, Phoenix, Arizona

### **Independent Consultant**

Performed a wide range of security consulting services as an independent contractor. Work included technical editing, security auditing, security article journalism, and penetration testing. Work performed in United States and Japan. Routinely employed by New Dimensions International, Internet Security Institute, and Unitek Inc. as an instructor and designer for computer administration and security courses. Courses taught included Controlled Penetration, 'Hacker Tracker', Operating Systems, Network Security and other classes. Students have included Army Infowar Staff, several NASA labs, National Computer Security Center, Fortune 500 and others.

# SELF EMPLOYED, Los Angeles, California

March 1999 – May 1999

December 1998 – February 2000

## **Independent Consultant**

Employed by US Federal Government as technical consultant for the representation of Kevin Mitnick. Duties included examination of over ten gigs of evidence/discovery and sixteen hundred pages of witness testimony to assist the legal team.

Repsec Inc., Phoenix, Arizona

March 1998 – December 1998

## **Senior Security Architect**

Employed by RSI as Senior Security Architect in Phoenix, AZ. Duties included all manners of security consulting ranging from policy writing to penetration testing, coordination of security advisory releases with vendors and RSI staff, maintenance of a comprehensive bug/vulnerability database and research for security solutions as well as new vulnerabilities. Acted as POC to software vendors in dealing with newly discovered vulnerabilities.

Trident Data Systems, San Antonio, Texas

May 1996 – March 1998

# **Network Security Engineer**

Employed by Trident Data Systems (originally in Colorado) as a network security engineer. Duties included providing security assessment and risk posture analysis for commercial clients, general security consulting, continued upgrading of internal vulnerability database, continued research for new security solutions, guiding Penetration Teams, developing strategies and procedures for penetrations, and developing security policy for Trident and clients. Clients included Fortune 500 companies and US Air Force.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

I have written a wide variety of articles focusing on current security trends and news since 1999. These articles have been published on several sites including linux.com, SecurityFocus, SunWorld, IBM Developer Works, ;Login, Newstrolls, eEye.com, DevX, OSALL, Synthesis, ExGame Magazine, The Register and many others. A full listing of articles is available at <a href="http://attrition.org/~iericho/works/writing\_security.html">http://attrition.org/~iericho/works/writing\_security.html</a>.

#### **PRESENTATIONS**

- "Cyberwar: Not What We Were Expecting" (26 September 2012 Ghent, Belgium)
  A debunking of the rhetoric and hype that has dominated the topic of cyberwar for years, as well as a foundation of ideas that seem to be lost on the cyberwar 'experts', that effectively broadens the topic and should make everyone reconsider what they think they know about it.
- "Errata Hits Puberty: 13 Years of Chagrin" (30 May 2012 Richmond, VA)
  13 year history of the Errata project, giving a behind-the-scenes look at the nightmare and headaches involved. Both from the project, and from the security industry.
- "Anonymous 20\*20: The Beginning is Near" (17 April 2012 Boston, MA)
  Keynote about the hacktivist "group" Anonymous, implications of the group, and possible future direction they could take.
- "Hacker Court" (2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, 2007 Las Vegas, NV.)

  Mock trials of "hacker" crimes stressing current and evolving issues of computer law.
- "Everything is Vulnerable" (5 May 2005 Vancouver, Canada)

  Overview of vulnerability databases, strengths, weaknesses and why they have not evolved in the last decade.

Resume: Brian Martin 3

- "Multiple Topics" (20 May 2002 Manilla, Philippines.)
  Two presentations covering wide a variety of current topics related to security.
- "Mirror Image" (12 July 2001 Blackhat Briefings 2001, Las Vegas, NV.)
  A summary of the two and a half year project of the Attrition Defacement Archive, including detailed statistics on web defacement computer crime.
- "Plenary Debate: The Hacker Wars" (1 November 2000 COMPSEC 2000, London, England) Quiz the hackers face-to-face and find out more about the motives and demographics behind hacker attacks.
- "Reflections on the Attrition Mirror" (26 July 2000 Blackhat Briefings 2000, Las Vegas, NV.) A summary of the Attrition.org defacement mirror process, parties involved and associated pitfalls.
- "Current Hacking Trends" (24 25 April 2000, Tokyo, Japan) An overview of existing threats and solutions for network security.
- "Info Protect: Air Force Space Command" (21 25 April 1997 Peterson AFB)

  The demo included a live penetration of several UNIX systems, concept and theory of new and upcoming attacks, demonstration of Denial of Service attacks, and general Q&A regarding exploitation and vulnerabilities.

In addition, I have participated in a number of panel discussions on a wide range of security topics focused on both technical and sociological issues.

#### **EDUCATION**

Texas Tech University, Architecture/Civil Engineering, Attended 1991 - 1992

#### OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Internet Site Development and Maintenance - I currently administrate Attrition.org, a hobby web site operating since October, 1998. The site is known for its past work as a Web Defacement Archive, the precursor to the DatalossDB, and colorful articles about the deficiencies of the computer security industry. The site has received as many as twenty three million hits from over four hundred thousand unique viewers each month.

<u>Open Security Foundation</u> – President and COO of the <u>Open Security Foundation</u> (OSF), a 501(c)(3) not-for-profit formed to empower all types of organizations by providing knowledge and resources so that they may properly detect, protect, and mitigate information security risks. Primary role since December, 2003 has been as the Content Manager to the Open Source Vulnerability Database (OSVDB.org) and concept designer / contributor to the Dataloss Database (datalossdb.org).

**CVE Editorial Board Member** – Since September, 2009.

<u>University of Dayton Cybercrime Seminar</u> - Honorary Professor, 2003 - 2004

<u>Call-For-Papers (CFP) Reviewer</u> - Review and guide information security conferences on submitted talks. This includes BSidesDFW 2012, BSides Denver 2013, BSides Las Vegas 2013, BSidesATX 2013, RVASec 2012/2013, and DEFCON 21.